### Matthew Judd

# Digital content and project management

11 Marshall Street Newtown, 3220 0466 805 442 matt@juddcentral.net

Folio: mattjudd.github.io/folio/

An experienced digital content producer with a core background of publishing and web development - a career history that extends to web, print, and TV at leading companies in London, Melbourne, and Wellington.

At home with both online and print publishing, having produced high-quality content in fast-paced, deadline-driven environments.

#### Flagship work includes:

- end-to-end digital campaign management: client, stakeholder, and schedule management; campaign web content, EDMs, and analytics;
- producing AWS server-based HTML/CSS/JS/PHP templates for generating personalised data-responsive videos;
- website content management and governance;
- designing and producing a publishing database for TheLancet.com scheduling management;
- repurposing content into eBook packages for Amazon, iBooks, and Kobo;
- migrating the archive of *Lancet* online content into a new global CMS.

Recognised among colleagues for initiative, approachability, and "getting it done".

#### Skills

A largely self-taught digital content producer, I have worked within many large-scale international CMS, each custom-built for the company concerned.

I am proficient enough in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and PHP. I can manage Git repositories, AWS services, and databases. I have worked with and helped integrate API arrangements.

An Adobe CS, Google, and Microsoft Office professional, I am considered advanced in most digital management software.

**Project management:** practising Agile, and trained in PRINCE-2. I have used Jira, DaPulse, Accelo, Trello, Slack, and BitBucket management tools. My current favourite is Asana.

#### **Experience**

#### **Visual Domain -** Web campaign manager and developer

SEPT 2015 - PRESENT, MELBOURNE

As campaign manager, I personally handle end-to-end management of all web campaigns: bringing together internal and external stakeholders, front-end deliverables, back-end infrastructure, scheduling, analytics, and client satisfaction

I continue to be the lead front-end developer for the company's data-responsive video templates using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.

#### Additional functions

- Content management: Designing, UX, and building responsive campaign landing pages and online forms/dashboards;
- Managing Amazon Web Services (AWS) EC2, S3, and SQS services;
- Git repository management;
- Building and managing EDM sends;
- Staff training.

## **TheLancet.com @ Elsevier Ltd** - Digital content and project manager, Global E-Operations department

JAN 2014 - JULY 2015, LONDON, UK

Digital content management, development and campaigns on TheLancet.com, driving content through Elsevier's global CMS.

Working with 80+ internal and external stakeholders (editorial, production, marketing, technical, international), providing support, and resolving issues.

The Lancet.com presents original academic research across many independent *Lancet* journals, hundreds of themed medical research series and editorial campaigns, while interlinking content with complementary multimedia. A world-leading medical research publisher, *The Lancet's* content is deadline-driven, frequently time-sensitive, and follows strict international embargo rules.

#### **Projects**

- Scheduling database: proposed, designed, produced. A web-based database with secure login, global access, data submission management, reporting features. An agile project.
- Integration and redesign of established workflows (internal and external) into Elsevier's Production Tracking System (PTS). Significant compatibility issues, cross-department stakeholders.

#### Additional roles

- Local Application Manager: Designated Lancet expert on PTS and associated databases. A company role, part of an international collective of LAMs that meet regularly, occasionally in Amsterdam.
- Staff management: supervision, training, workload allocation, support of contract staff.
- Lancet staff representative: on the Elsevier UK Staff Council (3+ years)

#### Regular responsibilities

- Multi-platform content management for web, primarily via Literatum a customised global CMS.
- Scheduling, quality control, and communication across editorial, marketing, PR, and production departments.
- Suppliers: close relationship with external suppliers in Chennai, India, and California, USA.
- International stakeholders: regular logistics collaboration with Elsevier colleagues in Amsterdam, St Louis, New York, Oxford.
- Creative design as the occasion demands it: eg, a social-media-friendly infographic hub.
- Cross-browser and device testing; A/B testing.
- Supporting the Marketing team's EDM campaigns

### **The Lancet journals @ Elsevier Ltd -** Senior Production Editor, eBook producer

OCT 2010 - DEC 2013, LONDON, UK

Seven independent Lancet titles, primarily responsible for the weekly flagship journal: *The Lancet*. Working in a networked Adobe Creative Suite production environment, I managed content and produced page composition to daily, weekly, and monthly deadlines for web and print delivery.

 Designed, produced, and published The Lancet's first eBook titles: released on Amazon's (Kindle) and Apple's (iBooks) global stores, leading to 15000+ downloads worldwide in first 9 months



Participating in UAT for The Lancet iPad app

#### **SAGE Publications - Production Editor**

APRIL 2008 - OCT 2010, LONDON, UK

Coordinating production of internationally distributed engineering journals, from editorial acceptance through to publication online and in print.

#### **VisitBritain Publishing - Media administration**

2007 - 2008, LONDON, UK

A 'jack-of-all-trades' in media administration: managing CMS, contributing to PR, research, XML/HTML editing, distribution, eCommerce databases, and marketing of 15 VisitBritain titles and three VisitBritain websites.

#### New Media Age, Centaur Communications - Researcher

2007, LONDON, UK

New Media Age was a weekly B2B publication, releasing highly regarded annual Top 100 Guide to Interactive Agencies. I collated information on 250+ UK-based new media agencies, leading to researching, writing and/or editing 100+ profiles.

#### **Education**

**RMIT** - BA (Media) — literature and media production

1999 - 2004, CITY CAMPUS, MELBOURNE

#### **Awards**

**(2010) Young Publisher Grant** recipient from the Society for Scholarly Publishing to attend their annual conference in San Francisco, June 2010.

**(2002) Tony Staley Award** for best Australian community program (2002). Assistant Producer/Editor/Floor Manager, *Dawn's Crack*, Saturday morning variety TV, Channel 31, Melbourne.